What's the last 12 hours or so?
>> Uh, a lot of feelings, a lot of
emotions.
You know, when I got my name called, I
mean, it was kind of a a blessing, but
also, you know, was kind of thankful for
that moment cuz all the hard work my
parents had put in for me to be at this
situation, you know, it's something that
I I've always wanted to give back to
them and to be able to experience that
moment with them. means a lot to me.
>> When did you realize this was possible?
Like this dream, you know, I feel like
when you go to IMG, it's probably what
you're usually thinking.
>> Was there a point before then when you
said, "You know what? I really want to
make a run at this."
>> It was my freshman year of high school.
We uh me and my older brother Francisco,
we both went to St. Tardino St. Thomas
Aquinus in California. And uh we were
just balling. We were just kids that
were hungry for it. And then we got to a
point where we understand that we're
we're actually good at something and we
can continue forward with it. We start
pushing for greatness. Um and that's
been our goal ever since.
>> What do you think would be the biggest
challenge with adjusting the guard?
>> Uh
I don't know.
Um
probably different techniques than the
tackle. Uh, but I've been training,
cross training my whole
training process, not only for the
combine, but after the combine. So, I
feel confident in my skills and ready to
learn a lot more.
>> What made you do that? Cross.
>> You said what?
>> What made you cross train?
>> Uh, just making myself as valuable. Uh,
if you learn all five positions, I mean,
I'm hungry for a spot. So,
it's not, you know, it's not fair for me
to to just practice one spot if I'm
hungry for anything, just to be an
offensive lineman.
>> What kind of questions have you asked
your brother, uh, having come come into
the league last year and whatnot?
>> Um, I haven't really asked him a lot of
questions. Uh, but he has been a great
mentor in my life. He told me to just be
myself. He actually told me that I'll
enjoy the league more than college. uh
just because school is out of the the
out of the story and yeah it's just
straight ball from now on.
>> I guess this did you were you familiar
with John Hall's you know when you
played you know he coached the Ravens
for nearly two decades.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I was Yeah, I kind of have a
snippet of it. Uh hearing the story of
him and his brother going at it in the
Super Bowl. Uh it's pretty funny.
>> What about this style? You know, you
ever watch the particular style that you
Yeah. I mean, the legendary Ray Lewis.
Um
I mean, that type of style of play kind
of, you know, comes up with with John
Harour and how he teaches thing. I see
him as a old school type of uh coach and
that's how I like things to be. Um just
hard, gritty, run through somebody, no
cut corners.
with Jackson a little bit ago. What was
that?
>> It was awesome, man. Really excited to
get it going with him. Uh to block my
for him and uh you know, get him to make
plays. It's he's so down to earth,
humble kid who loves fishing and yeah,
can't wait to get on the water with him
someday.
>> Did he like your comment, but you said
you basically died?
>> Yeah, he was pumped about it. He was
juiced up about it. uh he just told me
about it and uh yeah it's
>> I'm sure you've heard from a bunch of
different people and still checking your
phone hearing it. Saw something come
across social media last night that The
Rock actually reached out to you uh to
congratulate you.
>> Um I haven't checked social media yet.
Uh it's kind of hected so kind of
staying away from it. Just focus on the
main thing. Um, right now I'm here at
the New York Giants and I'm focusing on,
you know, what can I do to make make an
improvement.
>> Well, would you be surprised if someone
of that stature reaches that
>> you? Yeah, of course. I mean, D Rock has
been someone that I look forward to, I
mean, my whole life. Uh, he's he's one
of them idols that, you know, we see on
TV with movies, WWE, whatever he does,
he represents the Son culture. And
that's something that I like to do and
uh take pride in it. And for him to do
that at at the big stage that he is with
the Fast and Furious, I mean, it means a
lot. And you know, it's somebody that I
look up to. So for him to notice me, I
mean, it means a lot.
>> This obviously is very earlier just
you're here. Have you and your brother
talked about living together in the area
here or anything like that?
>> Uh we we haven't talked about it yet,
but if there comes a time, I'll, you
know, more more than likely move into
with him. Uh, but if anything, I I
wanted to stay closer to Oyer. So, 10 15
minutes away, that's my spot. But, you
know, it's up to him.
>> Have you been able to talk with any of
the other starting offensive linemen
like Germaine or any guys on the line?
>> Yeah. Yeah, Germaine reached out uh
after the draft, after the pick. Um,
really excited to be working with him. I
mean, he's a right tackle. They want me
to play at right guard. Um, and we're
we're out here to to move people and
that's what we're going to do.
>> You mentioned you and Jackson both being
from Utah. So, is that going to make
this bond a lot easier that both you
guys kind of come from a similar
background as far as statewise?
>> Uh, I'm actually not from Utah. I'm from
American Mo, but Jackson being near the
Polynesian culture and like endured in
that that part of the the
of the world, you know, um, it means a
lot. you know, he actually told me that,
you know, he wants more polies over
here. That's what he was trying to push
for. Um, and I was like, "Hey, man.
Let's start a pipeline." And, um, yeah.
>> I don't know how much you and Arll like
squared off in that playoff game, but
what's your scouting report of him?
>> Oh, he's one hell of a rusher. He's one
hell of a player overall. Uh, he's one
of the cats that can do it all. um when
I was watching his film, he was one of
the best rusher that came off on the
film and he's also one of the best um
you know defender that can cover people
up um make make plays downhill and stuff
like that. So it was kind of a it was
kind of the key player that we had to
look for uh during the game. I'm
wondering what kind of have you spoken
to anybody about playing guard or taking
advice from people on on making that
switch and do you have any thoughts on
that in general?
>> Uh no, I've been working with John
Feliciano um out of Knoxville Triple F.
But
>> what's been
>> uh it's it's pretty simple. You know,
tackle you got a lot of space that you
got to cover. Guard you got minimum
space. So if anything, he said guard
will be easier.
So just ready to work at it.
>> Do other teams see you as a guard or do
other teams see you as a tackle when
you're in the pre-draft process?
>> Uh
yeah, they Yeah, there's some other
teams that see me as guard, but I mean
like I said, man, it's five position on
offensive lineman. I'm ready to take
one.
>> Take a few more.
>> What's it like sh
Man, he's an amazing kid. I know he
don't smile much, but he's he's really
cool behind the scenes. Uh, having to
talk to him. I know he kind of explains
something about holding a grudge against
us. Um, Miami versus Ohio State, but you
know, what's in the past is in the past.
Now we're New York Giants. Ready to move
on from it.